# Janice Terpin Johnson



484-744-2643



jmtj.johnson@gmail.com



LinkedIn-janicejohnson

# HARD SKILLS

User Research
User Personas
Prototyping
Wireframes
User Testing
Web Design
Presentations
Digital Data Analytics
Digital Marketing

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

Effective Communication Leadership & Collaboration Empathy Human Center Design Problem Solving Critical Thinking

#### **TOOLS**

Figma
Adobe Analytics
Adobe Creative Suite
Marvel
HTML/CSS

# **PROFILE**

## Solution Consultant - Passionate about continuous improvement

I am passionate about applying my digital data and marketing experience with my creativity, empathy, and solution-finding mindset into my work. I continuously seek to create better user experiences for everyone, everywhere.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

January 2017 - April 2022

#### **Digital Data Leader**

Vanguard, Malvern, PA

- Lead digital measurement strategy to ensure quality insights on audience engagement of web, social, email and paid media. Collaborate with business partners to define KPIs, ensure marketing technologies have the necessary integrations, and apply best practices.
- Head a data and technology team creating lead generation solutions to advance our digital transformation of engagement scoring and data integrations for CRM, web and email until the enterprise marketing technology updates are fully implemented.
- Lead division collaboration on enterprise global solutions for marketing technologies to ensure the department's marketing transformation needs are being met.
- Developed strategy and led the execution of a tailored curriculum for the department's Analytical Learning & Development program to increase analytical acumen, including Test & Learn Class, Adobe Analytics Workshop, Foundational & Insights Dashboards Workshops, and weekly Office Hours.

July 2016 to January 2017

#### **Digital Marketing Consultant**

Wunderman

Led global email team executing 40-70 deliveries per week in multiple languages for a global travel industry leader using Adobe Campaign.

November 2015 to June 2016

## **Solutions Consultant**

Lima Consulting Group

Partnered with clients to deliver analytics, SEO, and campaign implementation. Responsibilities included creating analysis and insights reports with recommendations of content to publish based on research, seasonality, and past results; developing and implementing inbound marketing campaigns to attract potential clients.

November 2013 to October 2015

#### **Digital Marketing Specialist**

**KBM Group** 

Managed multiple clients' email marketing campaigns. Responsibilities included writing HTML for email, creating and implementing test campaigns, and managing live deployments.

- Reverse-engineered a new client's existing Responsys campaign for deployment
  and established more efficient methods for future campaigns. There was no
  documentation on how the complex campaign initially functioned. The campaign
  used over 90 driving HTML templates to display 200+ monthly offer modules across
  5 languages and was driven by a distribution list of over 8 million records.
- Transformed the campaign process with a design team to reduce the number of templates to 8 and still accommodate the 5 languages and 200+ offer modules using supplemental tables and dynamic content.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Expert Adobe Analytics
Business Practitioner
Certified Expert Adobe Campaign
Business Practitioner
HubSpot Inbound Marketing
seoClarity Certified User

# **EDUCATION**

Career Foundry
UX Design; Web Development
University of Notre Dame
BBS, Management Information
Systems
Andersen Consulting Professional
Training over 500 hours

January 2009 to August 2013

#### **Email Campaign Strategist**

SF

Executed advanced email campaign planning and operations; implemented email best practices; ensured clear content and layout; resolved application issues; provided support and training for each of the business units; HTML and basic Photoshop editing.

Managed the marketing email service application, Responsys, for SEI Corporate and its 5 business groups across a global market.

#### **VOLUNTEER LEADERSHIP ROLES**

Eighteen years in active volunteer leadership positions in five organizations:

- Email Specialist | DMAX Foundation Philadelphia, PA
- Board Member, Producer, Director | Spring-Ford Community Theater -Royersford, PA
- Organization Co-Chair; Committee Chair; Fundraiser Chair; Decorating
   Chair | Spring-Ford Post Prom Royersford, PA
- President, Vice President, Yearbook and Various Committee Chairs |
   Brooke Elementary Home & School Association Royersford, PA
- Advancement Chairperson | Cub Scout Pack 231 Royersford, PA